## SURENDRAN GOPINATHAN



www.linkedin.com/in/surendran-gopinathan



79 Elmwood downs, Magheranan, Letterkenny

+353 899434636

surendran17.02@gmail.com

# **SUMMARY**

PROFESSIONAL Creative Senior Software Engineer offering 4 years of experience working in a SCRUM environment as part of Integration team in Pharmaceutical sector. Thrives within tight deadlines by applying agile development strategies.

Self Learner and Highly Adaptable to change and new platforms.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Senior Software Engineer

May 2019 - Aug 2022

#### Accenture

- Designing and developing solutions as part of middleware/Integration Team.
- Creating Workflows using Camunda Modeler to automate the existing solutions.
- Creating Database objects (Oracle PL/SQL) to handle complex business logic.
- Developing backend rest API's for web application.
- Managing Sprints in gitlab/Jira by creating and tracking issues with proper labels and milestones.
- Experienced in all phases of SDLC including analysis, design, coding and testing.
- Addressing business Critical issues that were affecting Customers and quickly solving
- Serve as primary contact for the client and maintain healthy relationship to guarantee continuous business growth.
- Actively listened to client objectives and concerns and ensured top quality deliverables
- Good understanding about Jenkins and Gitlab CI/CD Pipelines.

#### Associate Software Engineer Aug 2018 - Apr 2019

#### Accenture

- Consult with users, management, and technical personnel to clarify business issues, identify problems and suggest changes/solutions
- Support incident management and problem management.
- Creating interfaces using java and pl/sql to transfer/receive files.
- Manage and coordinate hot fix and maintenance releases.
- Provide support to the business during day-to-day activities and ad-hoc requests during on-call.
- Assist with troubleshooting and issue resolution relating to current applications, providing assistance to the development
- Providing knowledge transfer to new resources.

## **SKILLS**

- Java
- Oracle PL/SQL
- Camunda Workflow
- Python
- Restful API
- Git
- Maven
- Gitlab CI/CD
- Basic Unix/Bash

## INTERESTS

- Table Tennis
- Football
- Esports
- · Competitive Programming

## **EDUCATION**

#### Meenakshi Sundararajan Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering

2014 - 2018

8.01 GPA